WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Welcome to a special two-hour
penultimate episode
of Survivor 47.
Like any season of Survivor,
this one's been unique,
and it's really centered
around two big themes.
Number one:
a constant shift of power.
Every player in the game has
been on the bottom and the top.
The other theme is some
very savvy social gameplay,
which has made it
very hard to know
who's telling the truth
and who's lying.
And it's led
to some big moments,
like last week's
Operation Italy,
a beautifully-executed charade
that took Caroline
out of the game
and left us with six players.
A final six that nobody
would have predicted on day one,
starting with Andy.
Got off to
one of the worst starts
in the history of Survivor.
But instead of giving in,
he dug in
and he found his footing,
and he's still here.
Sam: he had power
early in the game,
but since the merge,
he's been on the bottom
and has had to play scrappy
every day just to alive.
Genevieve: she is social,
she's strategic,
she is cutthroat,
and everybody knows it.
And that's why she has
a very big target on her back.
Sue: she's got an idol.
Nobody knows about it.
But her real strength in
the game has come from loyalty.
And with the Caroline vote-out,
she lost her last ally.
And for the first time
this season,
Sue is alone in the game.
Teeny: she's been very open.
She's an emotional player.
It's worked for her,
it's worked against her.
But what has kept her in
the game are her social skills.
Finally, Rachel.
She's already won two
individual immunity challenges.
She has a Block a Vote and
an idol that nobody knows about.
That is a lot of power with only
six players left in the game
and she's gonna need it
because right now,
Rachel is the biggest threat
in the game.
All right, tonight we're gonna
have two challenges,
two Tribal Councils.
We'll go from six
to five to four,
and if you can get to four,
then at the very least,
you are guaranteed
a shot to make fire
and you got a shot
to win this game.
But all it takes
is just one mistake
and your game is done.
That's why Survivor
is so difficult to win
and so fun to watch.
All right, here we go.
♪ ♪
Previously on Survivor...
ANDY:
This is the defining night
for the rest of this game.
ANDY:
The goal is build suspicion
that one of you has an idol.
If we do that,
they will be compelled
to split the vote.
I'm most afraid of the idol.
CAROLINE:
So then, we would need
- to then split the vote.
- Yeah.
Thank you, Andy.
This is the biggest heist
of Survivor.
Yeah.
ANDY:
And we're calling it
Operation Italy.
PROBST:
If anybody has an advantage
or an idol
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
All right, I'll read the votes.
Twelfth person
voted out of Survivor 47
and the fifth member
of our jury:
- Caroline.
- Okay.
The tribe has spoken.
♪ ♪
SUE:
Tribal really sucked tonight.
Caroline was blindsided, so,
I lost my only Tuku member left.
I'm just so bummed.
Thank God that I have an idol,
because I'm in trouble.
Andy was supposed to be working
with myself, Rachel,
Caroline and Teeny, but
Andy freakin' flipped.
So right now, I want to rip
Andy's head off his shoulders.
Ugh!
So frustrated. So frustrated.
[laughing]
Oh, my God.
ANDY:
Tribal was incredible.
Operation Italy.
It went off to perfection.
And to sit here
having pulled off
the biggest move of the season,
this is the feeling you want
when you come out here.
Like, I'm playing
Survivor for real.
I'm actually doing it, and...
[laughs]
I love... It's-it's...
Okay, can I say,
I'm so happy to hear that?
I-I feel the love tonight.
- No.
GENEVIEVE:
Tonight, Sam and I were both
on the chopping block, so,
by all accounts, I should not
be sitting here today
to speak about the success
of Operation Italy.
It was such a long shot, but
it worked. [laughs]
Andy-- he is...
better at this game
than we all thought
or... we're all worse
than we thought.
SUE:
I've never seen someone
flip-flop so much in my life.
Just...
I have no respect for people
that just flip-flop,
but whatever.
I'm so pissed at him.
It is safe to say that not
one single thing went the way
I thought it was going to go
at Tribal Council.
Me, Rachel and Sue
all look like idiots
because we had a plan.
And Andy flipped on us. And so,
we need to talk right now.
Because what the hell, Andy?
That was insane to do.
Why don't we run this back
first and let's explain
- what just happened.
- Well, I-I thought of this
on the way to Tribal Council.
I was like, "This is better
in pretty much every way."
So, we spilt up Caroline, Sue
and Rachel.
TEENY:
It seemed like
Genevieve and Sam knew
you were going to do this
all along.
No. [laughs]
I know I need
to do damage control.
Teeny is feeling like I have
joined Genevieve and Sam
in a grand conspiracy
to take over the game.
That is true.
But no, no, no,
we can't let her believe that.
Those are, like...
SAM:
Yeah.
Right now,
there's six of us left
in the game.
That makes it
extra important for us
to recruit Teeny
as a majority vote.
Fortunately,
Teeny's kind of, like,
confused about what happened.
And so,
we play it off like
it was this happy accident.
The fact is, you lied to me,
thinking I was going home.
- Yes.
- Andy wanted to vote me home,
but then changed his mind
to save me.
So I told Genevieve to
play the idol, which was best
for her, but she didn't
trust me on my gut,
- so then she didn't play it.
- [laughing]
And then somehow,
we came out with the idol
- and Caroline went home.
- [laughing]
SAM:
I think Teeny, right now,
is in panic mode,
and she's very
vulnerable, and so,
Teeny bought it
every single step of the way.
So, it was...
chef's kiss.
I walked out
of that Tribal Council
just, like, smiling,
looking at the stars.
- I smiled and shook my head.
- And I... I was just like,
"How the ... did that happen?"
TEENY:
At this point, I have no idea
what my way
to the end is anymore.
I don't trust anybody anymore.
And with six people left,
there's really nowhere to hide.
At this point, this is...
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah.
- This is who it's gonna be.
If we get Rachel out,
this is who it's gonna be.
Even though me and Rachel
were working together,
she is the biggest
challenge threat at this point,
and she's the biggest
fire threat at the final four.
So,
my brain does make a switch.
I do want to work
with Sam and Genevieve and Andy
to get Rachel out of this game.
This is really a moment
of having to jump ship
and adapt in Survivor.
SUE:
Did Teeny go down with them?
So, when we got back
from Tribal,
Andy, Teeny, Sam and Genevieve
take off.
And I just felt like,
in that moment,
I needed to know
what was going on,
and I followed them.
I think one of the things
that you can't grasp at home,
because you always see
the, like, infrared camera,
and, you know, it feels like
there's got to be
a flashlight somewhere,
but you can't see anything.
It's dark.
It's pitch black.
- [laughing]
- GENEVIEVE: I don't
appreciate it...
RACHEL:
I mean, I couldn't see them.
I could only hear them.
- So I'm following their voices.
- [Genevieve laughing]
And I basically
crawl on my belly
underneath a bush
right next to them,
and I just listen
to their entire conversation.
SAM:
Sol saved her,
she took out Kyle
- with beating him the necklace,
she became the challenge champ
- Yeah.
- after him.
- She's incredible at challenges.
And I think she has
a really close relationship
with Caroline.
- So... she cannot win.
- She can't win.
- She cannot win.
- I think everything is kind of
crystallized,
and we just have to gun
for the immunity necklace.
So I find out so much.
I learn that
they're all gunning for me.
I hear my name.
I hear,
"She cannot win tomorrow,"
"Anybody but her."
- [laughing]: That's so bad.
- Genevieve, I told you
you do have nerves of steel.
When you didn't play that thing,
I was like, "Wait a minute."
RACHEL:
I found out
Genevieve does have an idol,
and that she has balls of steel
to have not played it yet.
Do you know what she's got?
Does she have an idol?
She does not have an idol.
She has a Block a Vote.
She can block somebody's vote.
RACHEL:
And finally,
when Teeny told Sam and
Genevieve about my advantage,
that's when I knew
that I didn't have Teeny.
But the good news is that
they don't know I have an idol,
which is brilliant in the sense
that they will never
see an idol coming from me.
I...
Okay.
RACHEL:
And so, with this information,
I have more legs in this game
than anybody at camp
realizes, and I can
hopefully turn this game around.
♪ ♪
SUE:
In the early morning,
I woke up, and
I'm feeling a little broken.
I'm just like,
"Oh, my God.
Like, put me out of my misery."
Oh, my poor Caroline.
I lost my girl.
It freakin' sucks
to lose my last number one.
I'm devastated,
but in the same breath,
it's something else
I just got to suck up
and just stand up
and start playing the game hard.
I have an idol,
but I want to find another idol.
I want to find an advantage.
I want to still keep searching.
I just have to believe
that there's one more thing
out there.
I'm looking for a miracle.
Yeah, on Survivor.
Is that possible?
Is it possible to find a miracle
on Survivor?
Are you okay?
I want to dig around this.
I want to dig--
Can we please dig around this?
- Hey.
- I don't care if that
something's happened here.
I have an idol.
I found it
day after the auction,
and I haven't told
a single person.
I'm sorry. You've been
digging up everything?
Mm-hmm.
- ...you don't
have to dig here, okay?
- Okay.
Rachel shows up.
She says, "Don't worry.
I have the idol."
And I'm like, "Oh, my God."
So now I know her secret.
She has
a Block a Vote Advantage
and she has an idol.
I feel I've-I've built
a good alliance with Rachel.
I trust her.
She's shared so much with me.
You cannot tell anybody, okay?
I'm not.
We cannot tell anybody, okay?
SUE:
But I'm not sharing
that I have an idol, too,
because everybody
wants her out, so,
I might be able
to hold it one more day.
If I don't win today,
I'm getting all the votes
because now that
I've won two immunities,
- I'm this huge threat.
- Mm-hmm.
- So I think that
we can trick them.
- Okay. Okay.
- I think we can do this.
- Yeah.
I think we have... we have...
We're not dead.
- Okay.
- Okay?
RACHEL:
It was scary to tell Sue
about the idol, but
at this point, I need Sue.
I have nobody else in this game,
and if I'm gonna pull off
anything, I need her trust.
We have to pretend
because Genevieve has an idol.
And so, I tell her my plan.
We have to pretend
like Teeny is still with us.
We have to act like we have
no idea that she has flipped.
I just want
to make them feel comfortable
so they don't know
I have an idol,
and I would kind of just be able
to, like, smoke 'em.
TEENY:
Tree mail!
All right. Day 23, immunity
challenge. Let's hear it.
RACHEL:
I need immunity
today so badly.
RACHEL: Oh, God.
GENEVIEVE: Oh, no.
RACHEL:
If I win today,
I think I can get
to the end of this game
because then I can use my idol
at the final five.
People, like, assume that
I would be down and upset
about my place in this game,
and yet, I am sitting here
with a grin on my face,
so excited
to just see
if I am able to, like,
just shift these pieces
into place
to get the result I want.
And so, I'm either gonna
smash this out of the water
or I'm gonna, like,
flail in the water
and drown trying.
Bob and weave.
Hey, you want to spend part
of your summer living
in the jungles of Fiji,
experiencing the adventure
of a lifetime?
Apply to be on Survivor.
♪ ♪
Bring in the boat!
- Oh, boy.
- I know.
Best kind of Survivor entrance
right there.
So, day 23,
the final six.
Let's get to today's
immunity challenge.
First things first.
Got to take it back, Rachel.
Second time.
Thank you.
Once again, immunity
is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna leap into the ocean
and then swim to a platform
where you will find a buoy
attached to a rope.
You're gonna maneuver that buoy
through a series
of obstacles
until you reach the finish,
where you will race to solve
a Survivor logo puzzle.
GENEVIEVE:
I know you do, Rachel.
PROBST:
First person to finish
wins immunity, guaranteed a spot
in the final five.
In addition,
you're playing for reward.
Want to know
what you're playing for?
- Yeah.
- Yes, badly.
- You'll be taken to...
...the sanctuary.
Where good things happen.
- Steak.
- Oh. Okay.
PROBST:
Baked potato,
wine, juice
and cheesecake for dessert.
PROBST:
You talk about fuel
to get you to the end?
This will do it.
Losers,
Tribal Council,
where somebody will be
the 13th person voted out,
become the sixth member
of our jury.
Big enough "steaks"?
- Yeah.
- [mock-laughs]
We'll draw for spots,
and we'll get it on. Here we go.
All right, here we go.
For immunity and reward,
guaranteed spot
in the final five.
Survivors ready?
Go! First you got to leap.
[Survivors grunting, shrieking]
That's how you do it.
Now it's a swim
to that platform,
and immediately start
working with that buoy.
You're maneuvering it
through a series of obstacles
as fast as you can.
Sam is ripping through it.
Sam is over quickly,
out to an early lead.
Here comes Genevieve
right on his tail.
Here comes Rachel.
Teeny with a sloppy fall,
but it's okay.
Sue's in the water.
It is Sam in the lead.
Now you're gonna be putting
that buoy over and under.
If this puzzle is close,
every second's gonna count.
Now it's Genevieve in the lead.
Genevieve moved quickly
through that second stage
with the buoy
and she's in the lead.
Sam right on her tail.
Here comes Rachel and Andy.
Genevieve's out of the water.
You're good.
Get up, Genevieve.
Start working on the puzzle.
Here comes Rachel
gaining on Sam now.
Andy gaining on Rachel.
Teeny gaining on Andy.
And here comes Sue.
Everybody's gonna be in this.
You got to get up on
the platform and start working.
There are all kinds
of puzzles on Survivor.
Some puzzles
come easier to others.
Sometimes you walk up,
and you go,
"Oh, this puzzle's all mine."
Everybody now working
on this logo puzzle.
You've been wearing it
on your Buff all season long.
You'll never forget this logo,
you win this puzzle.
It is Rachel out
to a very fast start.
Genevieve on her tail.
Genevieve with another piece.
Rachel with another piece.
Andy just gonna look next door.
"I'm gonna
let Rachel do the work.
I'll just see what she's doing."
Teeny gonna get in on that.
All that means is you're behind.
This is turning out
to be a showdown
quickly
between Rachel and Genevieve.
Genevieve with another piece.
Rachel with another piece.
Right now, if you were Genevieve
or Rachel, you got to keep
busting it, 'cause you got
somebody right on your tail.
Genevieve and Rachel
are ripping through this puzzle.
And another piece from Rachel.
Dude.
Genevieve with another piece.
Now it's Rachel
who feels the pressure.
It is Genevieve
clearly in the lead now.
Genevieve can feel
that momentum.
Rachel trying to catch up.
Nobody else even close.
You might have more fun
just watching like I'm doing.
Genevieve down to six pieces.
Rachel about double that.
Rachel with another piece.
Oh, my God, come on...
[muttering]
Guaranteed spot
in the final five on the line.
Genevieve down
to two pieces now.
Rachel with another piece.
Genevieve down
to one piece left.
And it's over. Genevieve wins
individual immunity,
guaranteed a spot
in the final five
of Survivor 47.
Wow. That was the fastest
I've ever seen
a logo puzzle put together.
Genevieve, come on over.
First individual immunity win
guarantees you a spot
in the final five.
- Yeah.
- In addition,
you've won an afternoon at the
sanctuary, where you are going
to fuel your body for that
final push to the end.
Choose one person to join you.
Already Sam is shaking his head
- saying, "Don't choose me"?
- SAM: Yeah.
My stomach
is in absolute shambles,
so, do not waste a spot
on me on the reward.
Let somebody
who hasn't eaten eat.
Um, so in that case,
I... I'm gonna take Sue.
PROBST:
Come on over, Sue.
All right, Genevieve,
you have one more spot.
- Teeny.
- Teeny, come on over.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, come on.
- Oh, my God.
PROBST:
Here's what's gonna happen.
Three of you are
going to the sanctuary,
three of you going back to camp.
Tonight, Tribal Council.
somebody will be
the 13th person voted out,
become the sixth member
of our jury.
It won't be you.
Bring in the boat.
[squeals]
Limo service.
- Fiji limo service.
- TEENY: Yeah!
All right, head over,
board your Survivor limo.
- Yeah. [laughing]
- Enjoy your afternoon
at the sanctuary.
- Thank you.
- Have fun.
GENEVIEVE:
Desserts!
PROBST: Enjoy.
PROBST:
Andy, Rachel, Sam,
got nothing for you.
Swim out. See you tonight
at Tribal Council.
RACHEL:
Genevieve beat me.
So, the majority of the votes
are going to fall on me tonight.
But I have a Block a Vote, and
if I play my idol, Sue and I
get to decide who goes home.
There is, like,
a pleasure in the fact
that Sue and I
have this power
over this larger group today.
♪ ♪
- TEENY: Oh, my goodness.
- Oh, my God.
- SUE: Oh, my gosh.
TEENY: Wine.
- GENEVIEVE: Oh, my.
- Run, Genevieve.
- Go, Genevieve!
Oh, my God.
Wow.
I'm going to inhale
every last bite of this.
- Oh, my God!
- Genevieve,
- thank you.
- [Genevieve shrieks]
I win this immunity challenge,
which I am thrilled about.
Never doubted myself.
JK. Doubted myself
the whole time,
but pulled it out,
and I'm very proud.
- Wow. I'll start by pouring us.
- SUE: Okay.
- GENEVIEVE: Thank you.
- Let's not waste
a single second.
- GENEVIEVE:
Pass me the juice, please.
- Yes.
TEENY:
I'll pass on the juice for now.
I got.. I got my juice.
- Let me know
when anybody wants a refill.
- SUE: Okay.
GENEVIEVE:
My main objective is,
have a nice time with
these two women that I have had
up-and-down relationships with
throughout the game.
I need to convince them
that Rachel's the biggest target
to everyone,
and I don't want
to push too aggressively
at this point.
I'm voting for Rachel.
I see her as the-the biggest
sort of obstacle
for me getting to the end.
What are you thinking, Teeny?
TEENY:
I will never beat her
in a puzzle.
I will never beat her in fire,
and I kind of want
to eliminate that option.
SUE: Genevieve and Teeny
are going for Rachel,
but I know she has an idol.
She's playing her idol.
So whoever Rachel and I
decide to vote for
will go home tonight.
- GENEVIEVE: Um, I'm gonna die.
- Let Teeny fill up.
GENEVIEVE:
I'm not filling up anymore.
- Did you put more wine
in our glasses?
- Yes.
[laughing]
GENEVIEVE:
Yeah.
Okay, so when we get back
to camp, what do I tell Rachel?
- Oh, yeah.
- I think she knows.
That's something I also wanted
to say to you is that, like,
when you didn't play that idol,
I was...
[laughing]: I have
a secret idol that no one...
Oh! Hmm.
The hypothetical idol
that I don't know exists.
Because I had a little red wine
in my system,
I told Sue
that Genevieve has an idol.
And instantly,
I'm just face-palming myself.
And I just started to be
in good with Genevieve again.
So,
I know I made a mistake.
The red wine's talking now.
I've revealed myself
as the 23-year-old I am
in that I can't
get a few drinks in me
without spilling the secrets
that are really,
really important
to people in this game.
You did good, girl.
- Good job.
- Thank you.
Teeny has now let
my idol secret spill to Sue.
I don't care.
It's not an idol.
But the more people
that think it is, the better
for my game.
I mean,
I should be thanking you.
This is amazing
for my game.
Great job.
Keep it up.
I'll give you a refill here.
Tell her more about how real
this fake idol is. Go for it.
- [burps] Sorry.
- [laughs] Oh, my...
There's an undeniable amount
of good fortune
hitting me on day 23.
RACHEL: Think you can
beat Genevieve, Sam?
No.
Why'd you guys
all hand her the ... game?
'Cause I think you both
could have beat me
more... better than you could
have beaten Genevieve.
And I don't understand.
- How do you feel
about your big move, Andy?
- [weak chuckle]
SAM:
It's three Gata members--
me, Andy and Rachel--
sitting on a beach, day 23.
We've all kind of been on this
roller coaster of a game,
weaving in and out
of one another,
coming after one another,
trying to work in harmony.
And so, this is an opportunity
with Rachel
to clear the air,
to lay out all my cards.
Like, I feel like I laid a lot
of my cards out for you
because I was looking for,
like, who wanted
to play the game with me.
I feel like you heard me,
but wanted to play
with Sue and Caroline
and Teeny and Andy,
and I wasn't really
part of your plans.
So, I had to find another way
to move forward in the game,
so...
I do think you would
win the game if you got there.
It might be difficult for you
to see, being you, but...
It is difficult for me to see.
SAM:
Today was the first time
in the game
that I've been very direct
with somebody
about where
my vote was gonna go.
And you're always
hesitant in Survivor
to, like, let your target know
that they're your target.
That could backfire on you.
But in the moment, it just
kind of felt right to me.
It felt like
the closing
of the book of Gata.
It's hard decisions, man.
I know. I don't...
None of it's personal.
Like, just know that, like,
I'm pissed, but I'm pissed
because I'm just like,
"God, this is close." You know?
- Yeah.
- Sucks to get this close.
It sucks to...
Yeah, you're right.
RACHEL: Just sitting there
with these two guys
who I've been with
since day one--
it's a little bittersweet.
Genuinely, this is a game to me,
and it always has been.
So... like, I love you guys.
We will hang out after this.
- [laughs]
- Yeah.
And I'm not mad at you.
I'm mad at myself.
Today was my ... challenge
to lose, and I'm so mad.
I'm so mad that I lost it.
I knew everything
was riding on it.
There's, like, a brotherly sense
to them, right?
We've been here for 23 days,
but it genuinely
feels like I've known these guys
for, like,
at least a year or two
at this point.
And so, I think today,
it just kind of all hit.
These challenges
are wildly unpredictable.
RACHEL:
I know, but it's a puzzle, man.
But at the same time,
it's just kind of this really
funny dynamic where I'm kind of,
like, playing into
my, you know, "imminent death."
And yet,
I know I'm not dying tonight.
I'm gonna be
waking up here tomorrow
and one of them won't be.
[sniffles]
[laughs]
But if I do not have
to play this idol tonight,
I get to play it tomorrow
and guarantee myself fire,
which is even better for me.
And so, I want
to connect with Andy.
I want to be real
with Andy, and...
I want him to kind of try and
see my perspective and see why
Sam is a better vote
than me tonight.
From what I've heard when
people chatter about Andy...
Mm-hmm.
...it's never been in the sense
of, like, you're a threat.
- Mm-hmm.
- And so, I think
you do have an uphill battle.
- Yeah.
- And I think
if you and Sam
sat there tonight,
- Yeah.
- as the final two,
he would win, hands down.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
I just think right now,
- the perception of you
with the jury is relatively low.
- Mm-hmm.
- It's not, like, bad.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
But it's also not good.
And I think Sam has...
...better relationships,
and I think that
I would lose votes to him,
- even if I sat next to him.
- Yeah.
ANDY: It's very clear
that the conventional
long-running narrative is
that I am not a threat, and Sam
is a threat, and Sam is a threat
because he is someone
who can definitely garner
a lot of jury votes
in the end of the game.
Your superpower is that the way
you move around the world
is, like,
a little careless, genuinely.
And.... because of that,
- people underestimate you.
- Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
I'm sick of it.
I'm sick of being underestimated
in this game,
because you just want
to be out here,
and you want to be known
as a capable player.
I think
you do have a better story
against me
than you do against Sam.
You've deceived me
multiple times.
ANDY:
I've gained a lot of confidence
in my decision-making, but I can
kind of maybe
feel the pressure of
how important
this vote is for my game.
I'm-I'm pretty sick of lying
to you, though. I don't like it.
So, I don't have an answer
right now.
Yeah, no rush.
ANDY:
At this point,
I need my perception to turn.
So,
I'm closing zero doors
right now.
Absolutely zero doors, and
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
[laughs]
♪ ♪
SAM:
Hi.
- ANDY: How was it?
- Good.
- Hello, Beka.
- SAM: Hello.
TEENY:
Full.
GENEVIEVE:
Coming back to camp,
I need to make sure
that the obvious, easy vote
of Rachel stays the vote.
And the thing
that worries me is
when things feel obvious
and easy,
that's when players
think "maybe now is a good time
to do something," you know?
And I want to make sure
everyone knows,
"Tonight, let's not
do something crazy.
Let's just do Rachel."
- What do you mean?
- You mean she yelled at you?
She's like, "I hope you enjoyed
your move last night."
- Oh, I'm sorry, Andy.
- ANDY: That's okay.
It was literally, like,
we sat there
and acknowledged the fact
that we were voting her out.
- Did you?
- Yeah.
SAM:
Right now, I feel very uneasy.
I think
I'm Rachel's target tonight.
Rachel's coming after me.
She doesn't realize how big
of a threat Andy is right now,
and Genevieve is immune, so,
I think if there's
a hiccup tonight,
I'm in a lot of trouble.
Andy, what are you thinking?
- Truth-Truthfully?
- SUE: Yeah.
This is the endgame.
I'm weighing my options.
Would we be, like, a final three
if I were to vote with you?
- Yes.
- We'd be a final three?
I mean, we don't have loyalty
to any of those other people.
- Right.
- Yeah.
And no one else
has given us a bone.
Yeah.
RACHEL:
I would not vote you out
tomorrow if you saved me today.
- Mm-hmm.
- I promise you that.
You promise?
I promise.
Do you promise him that?
I promise that I will not
vote you out tomorrow.
ANDY:
The logistics of Rachel's pitch
are pretty clear.
With her Block a Vote Advantage,
you do the numbers,
it's not hard to see that
Rachel just needs two people
on her side,
and she believes
she has Sue already.
So if she could
just swing just me,
just little old me, over to her,
then we can become the majority
on a final five.
Now... that's interesting.
- Yeah.
- RACHEL: I think
that it was clear that
you're in dead last because
Genevieve would have taken Sam.
She didn't.
She then took Teeny and Sue
- and not you.
- Yeah.
If I look at this game so far,
I've been on a real hot streak,
and I've been pulling off
really cool moves
that I could sell to a jury.
And so, what if I go
with Rachel and Sue?
What if I knock someone out
that I've been working with
very recently?
I mean, that's
a pretty bold move.
- Yeah, it's a big decision
for me, for sure.
- Yeah.
ANDY:
This decision is, like,
it's game-breaking
if it's not correct.
And if I make
the right decision,
I think I'm ready to just
keep hitting my stride, and...
and go on to win this game.
SUE: You have to.
You have to play your idol.
I was hoping...
- You're not swaying them.
- Okay.
- They're all against you.
Teeny's against you, too.
- I believe you.
- I promise you.
- I know she is.
I was hoping...
Andy's a very rational player.
I was hoping by appealing...
No, he ratted you out.
He just told everybody
what you said to him.
Everything.
- Don't trust him.
- Okay.
SUE:
My loyalty to Rachel is real,
and so, I'm gonna go with
what she wants to do.
Every single person
thinks that Rachel is
absolutely going home.
Yes.
- It'll be announced
before the vote?
- No, it'll be when he goes
- up to the booth,
it will just say he can't vote.
- Okay.
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
SUE:
Meanwhile,
I know she has an idol,
and I know she's gonna freakin'
burn them so bad.
My brain's been going nuts
all day,
'cause I'm thinking,
weighing my options.
Um, but...
it's best for me
to vote you out tonight.
Okay.
And I want to say
a couple things about that.
In terms of
my move last night,
I do feel like I have
maybe some more information
that is influencing
these decisions
- Okay.
- than it appears now.
And so, I would ask you,
as a friend,
to keep a little bit
of an open mind
to some of the decisions
I'm making, and...
Yeah, you'll be on the jury,
but I want...
I actually care more
about you respecting me
- because I... because of
how much I respect you.
- Okay.
RACHEL: I know
I'm not going home tonight, but
clearly, everyone thinks
I don't have anything, and so,
uh, I allow Andy
to tell me all about his game
and how he's been playing.
I think that there's a lot
that I've done
on purpose in this game
in which a final Tribal Council
would be a really good venue
- to talk about.
- Mm-hmm.
I would guess that this approach
from Andy is coming
from a place of jury management.
He thinks that I'm heading
to the jury next.
And hearing Andy
kind of talk about himself--
it does give me pause.
I started seeing him
as more of a threat than I was
giving him credit for.
And I wanted to just
- say goodbye to you.
- Mm.
Andy is trying to win me over,
but instead it actually
just made me question
whether Andy was a better option
to go home tonight than Sam.
On the one hand,
Sam has played a good game.
He's also the half of this
Genevieve-Sam impenetrable duo,
and that's dangerous
for my endgame.
On the other hand, I think Andy
is playing a much better game
than anyone
is giving him credit for.
Andy has pulled the wool over my
eyes three times in this game,
and I've fallen for it
every time.
So he is doing something right.
This vote
is very important because
I'm choosing the second
to last member of the jury.
And the fun part of this
is that I know
I'm not actually
going home tonight
and that they don't know
that one of them is going home.
I have the most power
that I could possibly have
in this game right now.
♪ ♪
Now bring in the members
of our jury.
PROBST:
All right, let's start
with the last Tribal Council.
Clearly, a massive blindside.
Teeny, did anybody ever get
to the bottom of what happened?
TEENY:
Well, there's been
quite a handful
of votes in this game
where I haven't known
exactly what was going on.
And yesterday,
I felt in a state of delirium
because I truly
did not understand
how Caroline went home
in accordance to the plans
that I had made yesterday.
And I feel like
it was almost an accidental
sort of situation
that happened. And I know
that's hard to explain
and put a finger on, but that's
- how I feel it happened.
- PROBST: Sam, do
you concur with that--
- it was kind of an accident?
- SAM: Yeah, I mean,
it feels like there was a lot of
people sort of disconnected on
what their role
in a particular plan was.
So, like, even those of us
that ended up with our plan
coming to fruition
were a bit surprised
- at how it came to fruition.
- RACHEL: Jeff,
can I call ...?
[laughs]
- PROBST: Yeah.
- Andy flipped.
- Like, that's what happened.
- Yeah.
Like, I don't know why we're
pretending like we don't know
what happened.
Like...
But I had no idea
that Andy was gonna do it.
I'm not saying you knew
that that was the vote,
but I'm saying that,
like, you guys
were targeting Caroline
and Andy was supposed
to vote Genevieve,
and he voted Caroline.
So,
I don't understand where
the confusion is coming from.
Does that line up for you, Andy?
I think what the confusion
that people are talking about
is that there are plans,
and then there's layers
within other plans.
- But Rachel was very direct
and simplified it.
- Yeah. Oh,
did I flip? Yes.
PROBST:
So, Rachel,
what was the fallout
in the context of the community,
the tribe dynamic?
Ah.
What a question, Jeff.
Um, maybe if you would ask me
a different day,
I would have a different answer.
But today was my do-or-die day,
and without
winning that necklace,
everybody that's
sitting here except Sue
looked me in the eye and said,
"I'm voting for you tonight."
"Like, we have to vote you out
because this and this and this."
And, like, you know, we kind of
had a funeral today for me.
PROBST:
Andy, is that how
it went down for you?
Everybody just told Rachel,
"It's you tonight"?
ANDY:
That did happen
and, from my perspective...
...I've lied to Rachel a lot.
I've lied to Rachel a lot
in this game.
I blindsided her three times.
We've had such up-and-down
strategic relationship,
mostly down, but a really
powerful personal connection.
And I look at Rachel and I see
an all-around
superb Survivor player.
So, I was just
kind of sick of lying to her,
even though
it's part of the game.
PROBST:
Genevieve, did you share
your personal feelings
about Rachel
- and why you're voting
for her tonight as well?
- Yeah.
And it's because--
and jump in if you disagree--
like, Rachel and I know
we are on opposite sides
of the tribe,
and neither of us
were going to bend
wanted to BS the other.
Like, we're like Voldemort
and Harry Potter.
We just, like, can't...
We're weirdly intertwined,
but one of us
has to die, you know?
GENEVIEVE:
But I'm not sitting
here counting Rachel out
because Rachel's
an amazing player,
and something
may still happen tonight.
So while we had her funeral,
she may rise from the dead
and-and come back, so,
- I need to vote for Rachel.
- Sam, how about for you?
SAM:
Yeah. Um, I adore Rachel.
We've tried to get our games
to align multiple times,
and that hasn't happened.
And so at some point, you'd say,
"I don't know
if I can work with you,
so I have to vote for you."
PROBST:
So, Teeny, was there
any other layer
this afternoon at camp
or was it just this:
"We're gonna all tell Rachel
"she's too good,
she's going home, and then
the community will decide
what's gonna happen tomorrow"?
I think a big part
of this decision
is having awareness
of your own game
and your own strengths
going into this end portion.
You know, we have one more vote
before it comes down
to fire-making.
I know my own skill set.
I know Rachel's.
Rachel is going to beat me
in fire if we get there.
So, it would be foolish for me
to sit next to her
in that position.
Sue, did you partake in this?
SUE:
Well, I'm-I'm the opposite
end of the spectrum.
Just like
with Gabe and Caroline,
I am not voting for Rachel.
Everybody else
knows that as well.
So, Rachel, if this is true,
and it's you tonight,
you spent 23 days
in the jungles of Fiji.
- What do you take from this?
- RACHEL: I mean,
this is something that
I've been dreaming about
for years, and...
it's been everything
I ever wanted it to be.
And I think the coolest part
about, like,
turning that corner
where I was just
allowing myself the freedom
to really play
is that I started
to actually have fun.
There was, like, a levity to it,
talking and laughing
and just slowing down.
And as I had a better time,
everyone else seemed to respond
to me a little bit better, too.
And so, maybe I don't need
to pack so much
into my life back at home,
and it will be
just as fulfilling, if not more,
is really what I've taken away
from this experience.
All right, it is time to vote.
Teeny,
you're up.
♪ ♪
Uh, you're an incredible
all-around player,
entirely deserving
of your threat level.
[reading aloud]
"...return to your seat."
I'll go tally the votes.
If anybody has an advantage
or an idol
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
You know, Jeff...
Think the only thing
better than
attending your own funeral
is knowing that you're gonna
wake up alive the next morning.
[laughing]
I'd like to play it
for myself, please.
Thank you.
This is a hidden immunity idol.
- Any votes cast for Rachel
will not count.
- Wow.
I'll read the votes.
First vote: Rachel.
Does not count.
Rachel.
Andy.
That's one vote Andy.
Thirteenth person voted out and
the sixth member of our jury.
- Nice.
- PROBST: Andy.
Need to bring me your torch.
It's all good.
I'm-I'm honored. I'm honored.
Andy, the tribe has spoken.
- Time for you to go.
- Good game. Good game, y'all.
- Good game. Good game.
- Bye.
- Bye, Andy. Good job, Andy.
Grab your torches.
Head back to camp.
Good night.
[laughing]
I got idoled out in Survivor.
But after the start
I had in this game,
I have my head held high.
It's just
an unbelievable transformation
that I've had over these
23 days.
And I'm gonna take it
with me, you know,
for the rest of my life,
and definitely for the better.
♪ ♪
RACHEL:
That was a huge Tribal for me.
I finally was the one
that knew what was going on,
and basically, no one else did.
And it was fun.
Like, I had a blast with it.
- That was a great job.
- Great job, Rachel.
TEENY:
Rachel with the first idol play
of the post-jury phase
of the game.
Great job, Rachel.
- Rachel...
- How long have you had that?
TEENY: Shut up.
- Oh.
- Can you explain, though.
- I would love to share,
but I also...
RACHEL:
The emotion
during that Tribal was
mostly just, like, glee.
We had my funeral procession
and little did they know that
I had an idol in my pocket, and
I would wake up
on this beach tomorrow.
My clue
was in my French fries
at the auction.
- That is amazing.
- RACHEL: Um,
I'm very curious
where you got yours.
- SUE: What? What?!
- You're frick...
No, you're lying.
- SUE: No frickin' way.
- Oh, my God.
GENEVIEVE: So...
So my idol is totally fake,
and only Sam is left in the game
that knows it is fake.
So,
I guess the age-old advice of
"fake it till you make it" can
even work in Survivor.
You just have to fan
those flames a little bit,
and before you know it,
everyone's believing
you've got an idol.
RACHEL:
I wanted to have the necklace
today so that I could
play my idol tomorrow.
You winning today
was my worst-case scenario.
- [laughs]
- GENEVIEVE: Well,
I'm sorry, Rachel,
but I'm gonna have to try
and win tomorrow now, too,
- Um, yeah, samesies.
- because I still have
a Rachel problem in this game.
RACHEL:
Genevieve and I
have kind of been
dancing around each other.
We both recognized each other
the second we merged.
I never trusted her
and she never trusted me
because I think
like just recognized like,
and we just knew
that we were gonna
be adversaries in this game.
I should not care
about getting firewood.
I know.
GENEVIEVE:
Rachel and I don't bother
hiding the fact that
we want each other out.
I definitely look at her
as someone who
I don't want to sit next to.
I think she will win the game,
and it sounds like
she may feel similarly about me.
And so, it really is one
of those situations where
this island isn't big enough
for the both of us.
And so,
it's Genevieve vs. Rachel.
♪ ♪
What time do you think
she went out?
- I mean...
Yeah, she might already have it.
Let's find out.
Day 24.
It's about time
we search someone's bag
for stuff.
- TEENY: Check the pockets.
- Yeah.
Nothing there.
As happy as I am to have
made it through Tribal Council,
I am so irritated
that Rachel
is still in this game.
I have been targeting her
for days and days now,
and she's still here.
Got to make sure
there's no surprises.
Last night was not fun.
Because Rachel played an idol,
I have to think
there is one out here somewhere.
And I know, for me,
I can't let Rachel get it.
GENEVIEVE: I don't think
it would be in her bag.
SUE: Everyone is thinking that
there is another idol out there,
and I'm, like, the smart one,
keeping my mouth shut that
I have a hidden immunity idol.
- Yeah.
- She's got it, it'll be on her.
SUE:
This has been my theme
this whole time from day one.
I know everyone's gonna
freakin' underestimate me.
And none of 'em
would even think
that I would have an idol.
I freakin' made it
to the final five
with an idol in my pocket.
Isn't it crazy?
Isn't this freakin' crazy?
She's had a lot of good luck
in this game.
- SAM: Yeah.
- She has.
If she wins today,
it's, like, damn.
I genuinely love this battle
with Rachel.
To have Rachel and I as, like,
two sort of similar
professional women
in their 30s going
against each other--
it makes me feel
really good about
season 47 of Survivor.
I can't see anything.
GENEVIEVE:
It's a little awkward
when I have to kind of
follow her around camp because
if she finds an idol,
it's gonna be a problem for me.
So, babysitting Rachel
feels a little icky.
I hate having to do it to her,
but I'm pretty open
about the fact that,
"I'm sorry, Rachel.
I have to follow you everywhere
and make sure you lose today
and vote you out."
If you find a second idol...
I swear to God, Genevieve...
It's a fun relationship
we have in this game.
The best frenemy
I could have asked for.
[laughs]
Mm. Agreed.
RACHEL:
Genevieve and I will be going
head-to-head,
but I'm happy to have somebody
that I feel like
I really genuinely respect
to, like, showdown with
in this game.
We are going
to clash, and we're gonna see
who comes out alive.
Here's my question.
If neither of us
make it to the end, who wins?
Sam.
I'm so proud of us.
- Final five. Like...
- Twenty-four. 24.
I will never get over it
in my life.
- Like, this is just insane.
- Crazy.
Twenty-four.
SAM:
Tonight's the last time
we vote.
SUE:
Okay. So, what bothers me
is that, last night,
- when they both came back,
they're just
- The two-- the two of them
- coming back here talking about
how great each other are...
- TEENY: Oh!
- Dude!
- SUE: To me, that's--
I can't stand showboating.
SAM:
Like, sitting in front
of the other three people
being like,
"One of us is gonna win."
- Like they're so confident.
- Like, I was like,
"You're really, like,
that sure that we all suck?"
- Yeah.
- SUE: That's exactly how I felt.
"Do you see that
we're sitting here with you?"
I'm very annoyed
at Rachel and Genevieve
literally thinking
they're the big threats,
they're the big dogs.
How they've done this, how
they've done that, and they're
just ready
to duke it out together.
There's three other people
still in existence here.
Like, what about us?
They think
it's only now a game
between the two of them.
- Yes.
- And whichever one of them
gets to the end wins.
- SAM: Yeah.
- And I actually just
don't think that's true.
Me too.
Yeah, it kind of made me mad.
Genevieve and Rachel
have been talking about how
they're the two best players,
one of them is surely
gonna win the season.
Okay, we'll see about that.
If I have anything to say about
it, that's not gonna happen.
♪ ♪
Come on in!
There they are.
Final five.
What's left of the community.
[chuckles]
So, here we are, day 24.
In your final five challenge,
arguably
the biggest and most important
challenge of the season,
because if you
win this challenge,
you can't be voted out tonight,
which means you can't
be voted out of this game.
At the very least,
you got a shot at making fire.
So, no matter what happens
in the final four challenge,
you have that certainty.
Big stakes.
- Shall we get to it?
- [all voice assent]
All right, first things first,
Genevieve.
- Got to take back the necklace.
- Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Mm...
Once again,
immunity is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna race in
from the ocean,
dig through
a massive pile of sand
to get under a log.
You're then gonna balance
on a wobbly beam while using
a long pole
to stack balls on stands.
If your stack drops,
got to start again.
First player
to stack six balls...
...wins immunity,
is guaranteed a spot
in the final four.
Losers, Tribal Council,
where somebody will be
the 14th person voted out,
become the seventh member
of our jury.
Let's do it.
We'll get it on. Here we go.
All right, here we go.
For immunity and a spot
in the final four
of Survivor 47.
Survivors ready?
Go!
First it is a sprint,
which on day 24 is
more difficult than it sounds.
Look at that-- Teeny and Sam.
Here comes Sue,
then Rachel, then Genevieve.
Now you got
to dig through that sand.
It's a big pile of sand,
and you want
to get through it quickly.
You know how
these challenges go.
Sometimes it comes down
to a few seconds,
so every handful
of sand you get matters.
Sue is through first.
Here comes Sam.
- Here comes Teeny.
- [grunts]
[grunting]
Rachel's through.
Genevieve in dead last
through the sand.
Now you're gonna
stack balls on stands.
You got to approach
from the back,
- Whoa, ...
- walk up that wobbly stand,
and then gently
place a ball and then a stand.
- Here comes Genevieve.
- Hate the sand.
[grunting]
...
PROBST:
Sue has one ball and one stand.
Rachel with her first ball
and stand.
Here comes Genevieve
with her first ball.
- Oh, ...
- These early ones are easy.
You got to use these early balls
and stands
to train yourself
to learn,
"How do I want to stack them?"
Anticipate what's coming,
which is six balls total.
And just like this game,
the longer
you get into this challenge,
the higher that becomes,
the more precarious.
Sue drops, got to start again.
- Oh.
- PROBST: Sam loses everything.
Got to clear the whole deck.
If you drop,
everything comes off.
Genevieve places another ball.
Rachel places another ball.
Damn. No.
PROBST:
It is Genevieve
gonna lose everything.
It's now Rachel in the lead.
Rachel loses everything.
Now it's Teeny in the lead.
Teeny drops.
We're virtually starting again.
This is one of those challenges
that's gonna be maddening.
- Oh.
- PROBST: You're gonna
make progress, it's gonna drop.
But if you're playing smart,
you're paying attention
to what you did wrong.
Everybody's gonna drop.
This is about learning
how to get better
at this specific,
weird Survivor challenge.
Genevieve...
places her fourth ball.
It's Genevieve in the lead,
by a bit, over Rachel.
Genevieve on one end,
Rachel on the other.
Right now,
in a battle for immunity.
Rachel places her fourth ball.
Genevieve has her fourth ball
and a stand.
So it's Genevieve in the lead,
Rachel trying to catch her.
It's another familiar situation.
Do you want to press it,
try to catch,
or you're gonna wait
for them to fall and just keep
with your game?
Genevieve placing
her fifth ball.
There are only six total.
You've got a fifth ball,
- Let go.
- then a stand and a final ball,
if you can get it to stay.
Rachel places her fifth ball.
Rachel loses everything.
The smallest vibration
on that platform can do it.
- No. I...
- PROBST: Genevieve drops.
It's now Sam.
Sam drops.
We're starting again.
Everybody is in this.
You cannot give up.
You got to dig in again.
Ugh!
Nope.
Ah...
Oh.
Rachel back out
with her fifth ball.
Here comes Genevieve
with her fifth.
There are only six total.
We're back
to a duel on the corners.
Rachel and Genevieve
have been making more
and more progress every round.
That's encouraging,
but it doesn't get you the win.
You've got to finish.
It is Rachel right now
coming back with her last stand.
Then one more ball,
and immunity is hers.
Genevieve one ball behind.
Genevieve continuing to dig,
hoping for a drop from Rachel.
Here comes Rachel
with the sixth and final ball,
guaranteeing her a spot
in the final four.
Genevieve trying to catch her,
hoping for disaster.
It's happened before.
Can it happen again?
It would be Rachel's
third individual immunity win.
PROBST: Here comes Genevieve.
She's got two things left:
one stand and one ball.
Rachel placing that ball.
It's dancing around.
Genevieve places
her final stand.
She has one ball left.
Rachel's placed the sixth ball.
Now she's trying
to get that pole out of there
without touching anything.
Then she has to
get off the stand
and back to the platform.
Genevieve right on her tail.
Rachel trying to keep that ball
- Don't worry.
- and stack in place.
Can she do it?
Genevieve drops
and loses everything!
It is now
Rachel's challenge to win.
All eyes on Rachel right now.
Does she have it?
- You go, girl.
- And she does. It's over!
- Rachel has won her third
individual immunity,
- So proud of you.
- guaranteeing herself a spot
- You did it, you did it,
you did it.
- in the final four.
- You did it.
Wow, what a challenge.
Well done.
Good job.
Well done, Rachel.
[sighs]
Rachel, come on over.
Good job, Rachel.
Beka woman.
For the third time,
individual immunity is yours.
Means you are safe tonight,
guaranteed a spot
in the final four.
You cannot be voted out
of this game.
- Thank God, Jeff.
- At the very least,
you've earned yourself a spot
in the fire-making challenge.
As for the rest of you,
tonight the dream will end
for one of you.
Fourteenth person voted out,
seventh member of our jury.
It won't be you.
Congrats.
Grab your stuff, head out.
See you tonight of Tribal.
- Thanks, Jeff. Can I have a hug?
- Of course.
Well done.
GENEVIEVE:
I'm incredibly bummed
that Rachel has won
the challenge.
Had anyone else won,
she would have been
going home tonight.
And now that's not happening.
So the best thing
I can think of is
I've got this fake idol that
everyone is afraid is real.
So,
it's not over yet.
It's not over yet.
♪ ♪
- Thank you.
- Go, Rachel!
RACHEL:
Oh, my God.
I won immunity
when I needed it so badly.
- SUE: That was a tough one.
- I needed it.
I knew I needed it.
Great for you.
Great for you, Rachel.
Genevieve, you're playing
your idol for yourself tonight?
We shall see.
RACHEL:
The last couple days,
I've been carrying around
this rivalry
between Genevieve and me.
And knowing that she's secure
tonight with her idol
and knowing that I was backed
completely into a corner,
drove me today to get it done.
Never in a million years thought
that that would be the case.
SAM:
I tried to tell 'em at,
like, the final nine,
but nobody wanted to listen
to little old Sam.
- [Genevieve chuckles]
- That I was gonna do well?
That you were gonna win the game
if we didn't vote you out.
RACHEL:
What?!
- Yeah.
- You did not.
SAM:
Swear.
Rachel wins immunity,
her third win.
The most defeating
of them all to this point.
Rachel's got her ticket
to the final four,
and my path to winning this game
got a lot more complicated.
If everybody
believes Genevieve is safe,
I'm probably
the most likely target.
But I know
Genevieve's idol is fake,
because I helped her make it.
And so, as close
as I am with Genevieve,
with Rachel immune,
Genevieve has to go tonight.
I might be making
a million-dollar
mistake right now,
but I'm gonna do it anyway.
And you might not believe me.
Genevieve's idol is fake.
- Seriously?
- I-I made it with her.
- At the final seven.
We made it on the reward.
- Wow.
- So...
- So she has...
- She doesn't have an idol?
Genevieve does not
have an idol tonight.
- A hundred percent confirmed?
- One million percent.
I made that thing with her,
and Andy knew that.
We showed it to him on the
reward, which got him to flip.
That make-that makes everything
make so much more sense.
Everything makes so much more--
Thank you for that.
SAM:
I can tell
Teeny's mind is melting.
I see her realize
in real time, "Oh, crap.
I've known nothing about what's
actually going on in this game."
I see confusion,
I see betrayal, I see fear.
And that's kind of the
exact reaction I'm hoping for.
I'm hoping that Teeny will feel
so betrayed by Genevieve,
so thankful to me
for finally coming clean that
there will be no doubt
in her mind what has to happen.
Genevieve has to go home.
TEENY:
So, we could get
Genevieve tonight?
We probably would have to
convince Rachel and Sue
that it really is a fake idol.
And then get them
to vote on Genevieve.
TEENY:
Wow!
I actually can't even
get myself to think straight.
My brain can't catch up
to all the things that I need
to unlearn about
what I thought was going on.
TEENY:
There was no clue
under a pizza slice.
Genevieve's idol
is fake.
It was never real.
I'm literally
rewinding the tapes
on every conversation
that I've had...
TEENY:
...and every opportunity
that I've let Genevieve
trick me and trick me.
Me and Genevieve are voting...
TEENY:
And it goes
all the way back to...
PROBST:
Fourth person voted out of
Survivor 47: Kishan.
TEENY:
...Genevieve voting out Kishan.
I don't understand
how they got
the numbers to do you.
No.
What is happening?
TEENY:
Then Genevieve decided
to get Sol out.
The tribe has spoken.
Why?
TEENY:
Then Sam, Andy and Genevieve
concocted one
of the most intricate
missions of this game:
Operation Italy...
Twelfth person voted out
of Survivor 47:
Caroline.
TEENY:
...fooling me
and getting Caroline out.
PROBST:
The tribe has spoken.
TEENY:
And I fell into
every single trap.
How could I have been so stupid?
If her idol is fake,
and I've been granted
the knowledge of that,
I would be a fool
not to eliminate Genevieve
and end this chapter
of her fooling me
with me getting the last word.
What if I told you
Genevieve wasn't safe?
The idol's fake.
Sam told me that Andy,
him and Genevieve made the idol.
SUE: You think she told him
to tell you that?
- 'Cause they're
scamming something.
- RACHEL: Yeah.
It's just a little bit fishy.
If Genevieve's idol is fake
and Sam wants us
to load our votes
onto Genevieve,
that would leave
Sue, myself and Teeny
voting for Genevieve.
Which means that
if the idol is actually real,
and Genevieve plays her idol
on herself,
now whoever
Genevieve and Sam voted for
is voted out.
So I should take her, or...
Um, let-let's not make
any decisions yet.
- I know. I know.
- Let's-let's...
- Let's breathe.
- get more information. Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
I don't believe it.
There's a big chance
this whole thing is a ruse,
and Genevieve's idol is real.
But I'm protected tonight.
I have my idol.
So myself, Rachel and Teeny
will make the decision.
Genevieve or Sam
go home tonight.
TEENY:
Rachel and Sue didn't buy it.
It's hard for any of us
to feel confident
in making the call
that we're gonna
put all of our votes
on Genevieve.
The only thing
I can think of to do to get
to the bottom of it
is approach Genevieve
with all the information I have
and give her the chance
to tell me if the idol
is real or if it's fake.
- I feel very confused.
- GENEVIEVE: Okay.
I feel like I've, like,
really been duped in this game,
and how wrong my gut
was in so many ways.
- Okay.
- Sam told me the idol is fake,
and it was in a pitch
to take you out.
Okay.
And I wanted to bring it to you
to hear what you have to say.
It is fake
and I am a sitting duck.
Dang it.
I really trusted him.
I'm incredibly bummed
that Teeny knows
that my idol is fake,
but perception is reality.
And so, if Sue and Rachel
do genuinely believe
I have an idol
and they believe
I'll play it for myself,
which means
they will put votes on Sam.
I have to write down Sam,
and he'll write down me.
Or if you want Sam gone,
you can tell them
you don't believe him,
and then we pile on Sam.
TEENY:
Genevieve confirms it.
I've got her.
I'm gonna be able
to take her out tonight
if that's what I choose to do.
SUE:
What's going on, Teeny?
TEENY:
But there is a possibility
she could have another
trick up her sleeve,
and they've
worked out this, too,
and it's actually a real idol.
- It's ...
- She was calculating out.
- There has to be something else.
- She's gonna put one on me.
- They want to split our votes.
- Like, you think
it's a real idol?
I think it's a real idol.
So what do you guys want to do--
vote for him?
RACHEL:
Do we just load on Sam?
SUE:
I'd like to load on her,
and she's either got it
or she doesn't.
TEENY:
Oh, my God. I just have no idea
- what we should do.
- RACHEL: I don't, either.
SUE:
I believe Genevieve's
idol is fake.
She's been playing us all along.
She's conniving.
She's actually brilliant,
and she's gonna do
everything under the sun
to win this.
RACHEL:
Something's going on.
They are bluffing us.
The fact that Sam
is pushing this makes me think
the idol's actually real.
And so, it would be a gamble
to vote Genevieve.
TEENY:
We've been duped so many times
by these people
that I don't know whether
we vote Sam or Genevieve.
My brain
is like scrambled eggs
at this point.
And that's not necessarily
the best state of mind to be in
when making a decision
that's as important
as the final five boot
on Survivor.
♪ ♪
Now bring in the members
of our jury.
[mouths]
All right,
let's start with the challenge.
We had another showdown
between Rachel and Genevieve.
Rachel, you pulled it out
for your third
individual immunity win,
which means you cannot
be voted out of this game.
You are safe tonight. You have
made it to the final four.
At the very least,
you'll be back here making fire.
So, congratulations.
Thank you. It feels amazing.
[chuckles]
- It should.
- RACHEL: Um, yeah.
I mean, today, I knew
that if I did not win,
I would be
out of this game tonight.
PROBST:
Genevieve, you had many chances
yourself to win it,
but close doesn't matter.
You don't have the necklace.
You're vulnerable tonight.
GENEVIEVE:
That I am.
And I was trying so hard
to beat Rachel because
I view her as such a threat
in this game,
and my, like, heart
was crushed when she won.
And so,
back to the drawing board,
because Rachel cannot
be voted out tonight.
Teeny, the last
couple of Tribal Councils
have been bananas.
Shocking blindsides,
blocked vote, idol plays.
And this is the last vote.
So, what was it like
this afternoon?
TEENY:
I'd actually like
to take it back.
Last Tribal, we were
all evidently surprised,
besides Sue,
by Rachel's idol play,
because before that, the belief
that I was under
was that Genevieve
was the only person in the game
who had an idol.
And I gained
a whole new perspective
on this game, and learned
some information from Sam
that Genevieve's idol
is not real.
So, I think there is so much
uncertainty, and the fact
that I ever believed the idol
was real makes me question
if I should
even believe it's not.
Wow. So, Rachel,
this is what happens
when you get this deep into
Survivor, and there have been
a lot of truths
and untruths spread.
You no longer
know which is which.
RACHEL:
Yeah. Today, we were
spinning
with conspiracy theories.
Like, "Genevieve has an idol."
"Is the idol real?"
"Are Genevieve and Sam
working together
"to try and get
the three of our votes
"on to the wrong person
"so that they control
what happens
if the idol is real?"
And trying
to get to the bottom of
what the truth is
was the topic of the afternoon.
PROBST:
Sam, one of the interesting
parts of this is
Teeny says, "I got all
this information from Sam.
I mean, I think
I got information."
SAM:
Yeah. I felt
it was in the best interest
of my game
to let that information
get out there.
And as I've learned
in this game,
if you want information
out there,
tell Teeny.
It'll get out there.
- Wow.
- TEENY: That's a reputation
I think I've had
for a majority of my life,
and I don't think any of
my friends would be surprised
to hear it,
but that's also the way
that I've chosen
to play this game.
And it's gotten me a seat
in the final five.
All I can do
is trust my gut tonight.
And right now,
I've never felt more confident
that I'm less confident
in what's going to happen.
But I'm also sure
that what I do tonight
will either lose me the game
or possibly win it for me.
PROBST:
So you're certain
that you're
completely uncertain?
Absolutely.
PROBST:
And you are certain that
it will either be good or bad?
You got it.
Genevieve just spun me
around in circles today,
like she has many times
in this game
and I'm sick of it
and I just want
to survive it one last time,
and that's where I'm at.
So vote for her.
I gave the blueprint. I said,
"Genevieve's idol is fake.
We can all vote for Genevieve."
And they don't want
to believe it.
- I don't-I don't really know
what the problem is.
- TEENY: Sam, me
and you haven't talked. I didn't
say I wasn't voting for her.
I'm just... Well,
I'm just saying,
if everybody's got a problem
with how Genevieve's playing
the game, vote for Genevieve.
And that's what I've been told
is happening.
- Everyone's voting for me.
- But it's also hard to trust Sam
because Sam and Genevieve
work together, and, you know,
- come up with crazy plans, so...
- RACHEL: I mean, if her idol
is real, and their two votes
vote out whoever they want,
- because we all
piled our votes on her.
- Get the picture?
Yeah.
It's Survivor.
I am sorry people
don't appreciate the spin
and they don't appreciate
the stories, but
what am I supposed to do?
Just go,
"Okay, game over. You got me"?
I don't blame you for doing it.
It's not a lack
of appreciation, Genevieve.
It's that I also want
to survive in this game.
And that's my response to it,
is feeling spun around,
but trying to...
advocate for myself
and make the best move for me.
It's not a lack of appreciation.
- Don't take offense.
- Okay.
Sam, from the standpoint of
the five of you looking
to win this season of Survivor,
is tonight's vote
the biggest vote of the season?
SAM:
I think they all get bigger.
The final three is not really,
like, a future plan.
It's, like, reality
because you're forming it.
So, yes, each one's bigger
than the last.
- Concerning?
- No.
I'm voting for Genevieve.
Everybody knows.
PROBST: And, Sue,
you seem very confident.
You're not concerned
about this conversation, either.
I... They know where I'm going.
And I, so far,
have always stuck to my word.
Are we ready to vote?
- I'm ready.
Are you ready, Teeny?
Couldn't be more ready.
I don't know what else
I need to hear.
All right, it is
time to vote.
Rachel, you're up.
♪ ♪
[sighs]
I'll go tally the votes.
If anybody has an advantage or
an idol and you want to play it,
tonight is the last night
you can do so.
I told you it was fake.
Aw.
- All right, I'll read the votes.
- SUE: Jeff?
I'd like to say something.
I found this immunity idol
that I would like
to play tonight for myself.
[mouths]
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
This is a hidden immunity idol.
Any votes cast
for Sue will not count.
I'll read the votes.
First vote:
Genevieve.
Sam. That's one vote Genevieve,
one vote Sam.
Sam. That's two votes Sam,
one vote Genevieve.
Genevieve.
We're tied.
Two votes Genevieve,
two votes Sam, one vote left.
Fourteenth person voted out
and the seventh member
of our jury:
Genevieve.
Need to bring me your torch.
SUE:
Good playing, Genevieve.
- RACHEL: Good game, Genevieve.
- Hugs.
Come on, give me one.
Sorry for all the spinning.
[Teeny mutters]
Nice.
Genevieve, the tribe has spoken.
They have.
Thank you for the opportunity.
- I had the time of my life.
- Thanks for being here.
- Time for you to go.
- TEENY: Bye, Genevieve.
- Good luck.
- SUE: Bye, Genevieve.
Congratulations on surviving
another stage of this game.
You can no longer be voted out.
Tomorrow you'll compete in
your final immunity challenge.
The winner earns a spot
in the final three.
For the other three,
at the very least,
you'll be making fire,
which means,
Teeny, Rachel, Sue, Sam,
any one of you
could win this game.
Grab your torches.
Head back to camp. Good night.
Thank you.
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
RACHEL:
This is the last stand,
the final battle.
PROBST:
Next time
on the season finale
of Survivor...
You want it, this is where
you step up and grab it!
- [grunts]
- SUE: I want to
scream! I'm so pumped!
SAM:
You don't want to play 25 days
and come up that short.
TEENY:
This is gonna be a bloodbath.
RACHEL:
My only option
is to kick ass.
I just got voted out.
Five is as far as I get
to go in this game.
But I am so proud
of how I played out here.
I exceeded my expectations,
and my expectations were high.
I wanted the million. I didn't
get there, but I did better.
And I'm more
proud of myself than
I imagined that I could be.
[roars]